[music]
[音乐]
Hello and welcome to lesson
您好，欢迎上课
two of the massive open and online course
大规模的公开和在线课程中的两个
on JDK 8 functional programming. The
关于JDK 8函数式编程。的
idea of this lesson is to give you an introduction to the streams
本课的目的是向您介绍流
API. Again my name is Simon Ritter,
API。我又叫西蒙·里特，
Java Technology Evangelist. In terms that the agenda for this lesson,
Java技术推广员。就本课的议程而言，
we're going to start with an introduction to functional programming
我们将从函数式编程的介绍开始
concepts
概念
and it's quite important to understand some the significant differences
了解一些明显的差异非常重要
between how we're used to programming Java
我们习惯于编程Java之间
for JDK 8 and how we need to think about things from a functional perspective
JDK 8以及我们如何从函数角度考虑事物
when we start using the streams API with lambda expressions.
当我们开始使用带有lambda表达式的streams API时。
We'll move from there into what we actually mean by
我们将从那里转到我们真正的意思
a stream and we'll look at the elements of the stream API
一个流，我们将看一下流API的元素
in terms of how you put it together how you use it.
在如何组合使用方面。
We'll then talk about some
然后我们将讨论一些
differences between streams when we're dealing with
当我们处理流之间的差异
streams of objects and when we're dealing with streams of primitive types.
对象流以及当我们处理原始类型流时。
This is one of the things about Java is it's not
这是关于Java的事情之一，不是
fully object-oriented, it doesn't have everything represented as an object.
完全面向对象，它没有将所有内容都表示为对象。
Sometimes we do need to think about primitive types and for streams there are
有时我们确实需要考虑原始类型，对于流，有
certain issues we need to be aware of.
我们需要注意的某些问题。
Then we're going to talk about where you can get a stream source from
然后，我们将讨论可以从何处获取流源
in JDK 8. There are numerous places where you can create a stream source from
在JDK 8中。可以在许多地方从中创建流源
and we'll talk about those as we go through that part of the lesson.
在课程的这一部分中，我们将讨论这些内容。
Then we'll talk about the stream interface itself
然后我们将讨论流接口本身
and what are called intermediate operations. Don't worry about what those are now,
以及所谓的中间操作。不用担心现在的情况
we'll talk about those
我们将谈论那些
as we go through the elements of a stream. The same with the next part, which is
当我们浏览流中的元素时。下一部分也一样
terminal operations,
终端操作
because again we'll talk about those when we talk about the elements of a stream.
因为当我们谈论流的元素时，我们将再次讨论那些内容。
The last part of this lesson is
本课的最后一部分是
about another class called the Optional class
关于另一个称为Optional类的类
and that has a lot of impact on
这对
certain aspects how we use streams but it's also very useful
在某些方面，我们如何使用流，但它也非常有用
in terms of other
在其他方面
kinds of code and we'll explain what you can actually use
各种代码，我们将说明您可以实际使用的内容
optionals for and that the different ways that they can be applied
的可选方式以及可以应用它们的不同方式
to different situations.
针对不同的情况。
Let’s start then with part 1 of lesson 2, which is about
让我们从第二课的第一部分开始
functional programming concepts. Now,
函数式编程概念。现在，
Java is an imperative programming language
Java是命令式编程语言
and, if we look at the way that we use Java,
而且，如果我们看看使用Java的方式，
specifically in terms all variables,
特别是在所有变量方面，
names and values we need to be aware of certain things.
我们需要了解某些事物的名称和值。
In Java we use a variable
在Java中，我们使用一个变量
to provide an association. What this does is it provides an association between
提供关联。它的作用是提供
a name that we can recognize and we can use in our code
我们可以识别的名称，可以在代码中使用
and value that's stored in association with that variable name.
和与该变量名关联存储的值。
What we then do is
然后我们要做的是
by associating values with variables
通过将值与变量关联
we can use those in a sequence of commands.
我们可以在一系列命令中使用它们。
Effectively, although you might not realise it when you look at your code
有效地，尽管当您查看代码时可能没有意识到
because you see loops, you see conditionals statements like if
因为看到了循环，所以看到了条件语句，例如if
else and so on, what you're actually doing
其他等等，你实际上在做什么
is creating a sequence of commands,
正在创建一系列命令，
which are assignments. You change
这是作业。你改变
a variable's value based on something. The way we would do that is with the
基于某些因素的变量值。我们这样做的方法是
equal statement, so we say variable name equals expression.
equal语句，所以我们说变量名等于expression。
The expression could be something as simple as X=X+10,
该表达式可能很简单，例如X = X + 10，
so we are adding 10 to X.
因此我们将X加10。
X=X++, that wouldn't be a very good example
X = X ++，那不是一个很好的例子
and X++ is better example because that's just incrementing the
X ++是更好的例子，因为那只是增加了
the variable, which is equivalent to X=X+1.
变量，等效于X = X + 1。
X equals the result of calling
X等于通话结果
process a value on X, so we can call a method
在X上处理一个值，所以我们可以调用一个方法
and that's another form of
这是另一种形式
expressions. Expression can refer to other variables,
表达式。表达式可以引用其他变量，
so if I want to process X , I can also pass y
所以如果我想处理X，我也可以传递y
as another part of the way that I want to
作为我想要的方式的另一部分
process it. There's numerous different ways we can do that,
处理它。我们可以通过许多不同的方式来做到这一点，
but it allows us to have complete flexibility over how we use
但它使我们在使用方式上具有完全的灵活性
other variables. What we can do with that is we can actually
其他变量。我们可以做的是实际上
use the value based on changes that have been made in the past.
根据过去所做的更改使用该值。
By the sequence of commands we can gradually change different values
通过命令序列，我们可以逐渐更改不同的值
and when we get to a certain point we then have
当我们到达某个点时，
new value based on what's happened previously. so the values that we got
基于先前发生的事情的新价值。所以我们得到的价值
can, in effect be passed from command to command
实际上可以从命令传递到命令
by using variables to represent them.
通过使用变量来表示它们。
If we want to repeat particular command
如果我们要重复特定的命令
we can do that either explicitly by simply saying
我们可以通过简单地说清楚地做到这一点
X=X+10, the next line X=X+10, the next line X=X+10 and so on.
X = X + 10，下一行X = X + 10，下一行X = X + 10，依此类推。
Or we can use a loop, we can use a for loop,
或者我们可以使用循环，我们可以使用for循环，
a while loop, we can use a do loop and we can repeat
while循环，我们可以使用do循环，然后我们可以重复
certain commands based on some kind
基于某种命令
of evaluation of an expression to determine when we want to finish that
表达式的求值以确定我们何时要完成该表达式
loop. From a functional perspective
环。从函数的角度
this is the way that we don't do things at the moment in Java until JDK 8.
这是我们目前在Java中直到JDK 8才开始做的事情。
What we do is we base
我们做的是我们的基础
names and values in terms of our code on structured function calls
根据结构化函数调用上的代码的名称和值
and if you think back to the very first example that I used when talking about
如果您回想起我在谈论时使用的第一个示例
why we needed lambda expressions
为什么我们需要lambda表达式
I said that we could rewrite our explicit loop as
我说过我们可以将显式循环重写为
a sequence of method calls that were chained together and that's effectively
一系列链接在一​​起的方法调用，这是有效的
what we do with functional programming:
我们对函数式编程所做的工作：
we take a function and then we call another function on the results of that,
我们采用一个函数，然后根据该结果调用另一个函数，
we call another functional on the result of that and so on. We chain together
我们根据结果调用另一个函数，依此类推。我们在一起
these functions
这些函数
to give us a set of results. So each function receives the values
给我们一组结果。所以每个函数都接收值
from the previous function as input and then when it's
从上一个函数作为输入，然后是
generated results it passes them back to
生成的结果将其传递回
the calling function and ultimately it passes
调用函数并最终通过
back to the assignment you want for the
回到您要的作业
result. In terms of names that we use for functional programming
结果。根据我们用于函数式编程的名称
it's different to Java, it's different to imperative programming
它与Java不同，与命令式编程不同
because we only use names for the formal parameters of 00:06:46,760 --&gt; 00:06:50,470 our functions, and we can only assign
因为我们仅将名称用于形式参数 我们的函数，并且我们只能分配
that value once. So we assign the value passing as a parameter
该值一次。因此，我们将传递的值分配为参数
and that's it; it's not changed, its not modified.
就是这样；它没有改变，没有被修改。
The variable is set once, its value is set once
变量设置一次，其值设置一次
and that's it. There is no concept of the command
就是这样。没有命令的概念
in functional programming as we are used to imperative code.
在函数式编程中，因为我们习惯于命令式代码。
There is no idea of assigning values
没有分配值的想法
because you can change values simply executing a
因为您只需执行一个即可更改值
function and repeatedly calling that functional or other functions
函数并反复调用该函数或其他函数
from that function. There is no concept of repetition
从该函数。没有重复的概念
in the sense that we have in imperative,
从一定意义上讲，
Java code because we don't have a for loop, we don't have a while loop; we
Java代码，因为我们没有for循环，所以没有while循环；我们
don't have do loop. If we look at the difference between names and values
没有do循环。如果我们看一下名称和值之间的区别
when it comes to imperative code verses functional code. 00:07:42,110 --&gt; 00:07:47,090 In imperative code the same name can be associated with different values;
当涉及命令式代码与函数式代码时。 在命令代码中，相同的名称可以与不同的值关联；
that's the whole idea of a variable. In functional code
这就是变量的全部概念。在函数代码中
a name is only at ever associated
一个名字永远都没有关联
with one value. Execution order
具有一个价值。执行顺序
This is also very important from the perspective
从角度来看这也很重要
of imperative versus functional.
命令式与函数式的关系。
If we look at imperative code and how we do things in
如果我们看一下命令式代码以及我们如何处理
in Java before JDK 8 we
在JDK 8之前的Java中
associate values with variable names and those to be changed.
将值与变量名以及要更改的值相关联。
The order that we execute commands in
我们执行命令的顺序
forms a contract this again goes back to
签订合同，这又回到了
the very first example used in lesson one. By having a for loop
第一课中使用的第一个示例。通过for循环
where we iterate over a collection, the iteration
我们在一个集合上迭代，迭代
of that collection is in a defined order based on how the iterator works.
该集合的迭代器根据迭代器的工作方式以定义的顺序进行。
So that forms a contract with the compiler
这样就与编译器签订了合同
met with the runtime about how that data is processed.
在运行时遇到了有关如何处理数据的问题。
We can change that without potentially, changing the behavior the application
我们可以更改它，而不必更改应用程序的行为
and unless we know that we're
除非我们知道我们是
in a situation which could break an application code.
在可能会破坏应用程序代码的情况下。
so the compiler can't reorder things because it can't tell
因此编译器无法重新排序，因为它无法告诉
whether that would actually have an impact on the
这是否真的会对
results that generated. Functional code,
产生的结果。函数代码
remember, now we don't have names
记住，现在我们没有名字
associated with values that can be changed, so in this case
与可以更改的值相关联，因此在这种情况下
the order of the execution does not impact results.
执行顺序不影响结果。
We call a method from another method, we pass a function to another function
我们从另一个方法中调用一个方法，然后将一个函数传递给另一个函数
how that function actually processes doesn't matter.
该函数的实际处理方式无关紧要。
The results we get back will be from that function and the
我们返回的结果将来自该函数，并且
order in which it happens doesn't matter. So there's no
发生顺序无关紧要。所以没有
fixed execution order in terms what happens underneath
固定的执行顺序，根据下面发生的情况
in the way that function is processed in way that method is processed.
以处理方法的方式处理方法。
Which leads us to repetition.
这导致我们重复。
In our Java code, in imperative code,
在我们的Java代码中，在命令式代码中，
again we have values which are associated with names
同样，我们有与名称相关的值
and they can be changed by commands. So we can
并且可以通过命令更改它们。所以我们可以
repeat those commands using our
使用我们的命令重复这些命令
loop ideas of for loops, do loops and we can repeatedly change
for循环，do循环的想法，我们可以反复更改
variable. If we loop from X equals 0 to X equals 10
变量。如果我们从X等于0循环到X等于10
we're repeatedly changing X between 0 and 10.
我们在0到10之间反复更改X。
So the new value is associated with the same name
因此，新值与相同名称相关联
through a loop through repetition. In functional
通过重复循环。在函数上
programming the values we have associated with names
编程与名称关联的值
may not be changed, so again, this goes back to what we said earlier.
可能不会更改，因此再次回到我们之前所说的。
Now repeated changes are achieved by nested
现在通过嵌套实现了重复的更改
function calls so if we want to call the same function three times we call back
函数调用，因此，如果我们想调用同一函数三次，则应回调
function from the first function
从第一个函数开始
then we call the function again so that provides us with
然后我们再次调用该函数，以便为我们提供
a way of doing repetition but not in a controlled way
一种重复的方式，但不是受控方式
that we would have loop where you can specify how many
我们将有循环，您可以在其中指定多少
times it gets done. So in this case with functional programming
次完成。所以在这种情况下使用函数式编程
what we're actually doing to associate new values
我们为关联新价值所做的实际工作
with the same name is through recursion. we're using recursion
具有相同名称的是通过递归。我们正在使用递归
to provide this ability to modify things and pass the state back.
提供修改事物并将状态传回的函数。
We'll talk more about this in lesson 3,
我们将在第3课中进一步讨论这一点，
when we look at some examples of how to approach solving
当我们看一些如何解决问题的例子
specific types problems and why you would need to think in a more recursive way.
特定类型的问题以及为什么需要以更递归的方式进行思考。
Functions as values
作为价值的函数
This is really the reason why we had to include
这确实是我们必须包括在内的原因
lambda expressions in JDK 8 because
JDK 8中的lambda表达式，因为
lambda expressions as we saw in lesson 1, allows to pass
我们在第1课中看到的lambda表达式可以通过
behaviour as in the same way as we do
行为与我们相同
a value. In effect,
一个值。有效，
because functional programming allows a function to be treated as a value,
因为函数式编程允许将函数视为值，
which means that we can pass as a parameter to a method
这意味着我们可以将其作为参数传递给方法
or function then we need this ability in Java.
或函数，那么我们需要Java中的这种函数。
So we could do it with anonymous inner class, but the syntax was too
因此我们可以使用匿名内部类来实现，但是语法也是如此
complicated,
复杂，
the syntax was too verbose, we needed a simple way
语法太冗长，我们需要一种简单的方法
doing it, and that's what lambda expressions give us. Now we have the ability
这就是lambda表达式给我们的。现在我们有能力
to
至
pass behaviour as a parameter
通过行为作为参数
and therefore we can take a more functional approach
因此，我们可以采用更实用的方法
because we can use the lambda expression to
因为我们可以使用lambda表达式
to tell the method how we want to do something
告诉方法我们要怎么做
by using that lambda expression to represent the implementation.
通过使用该lambda表达式表示实现。
To summarise
总结一下
section 1 of lesson 2,  if you compare imperative
如果您比较必要的话，第2课的第1节
code verses functional their approaches
代码节对他们的方法起作用
are very different and we need to be aware that
有很大的不同，我们需要意识到
when we start using the streams API, when we start solving
当我们开始使用streams API时，当我们开始解决
the kind of problems we can solve. If we think imperatively
我们可以解决的问题。如果我们必须认真思考
then what we're doing is associating values
那么我们正在做的就是关联价值
with names which to be changed. so that's our variables and
带有要更改的名称。这就是我们的变量
we can change the value of a variable
我们可以更改变量的值
any point in our code so long as it's not final.
只要不是最终代码，我们代码中的任何一点。
In terms of the order of execution what we're really doing
就执行顺序而言，我们实际上在做什么
with imperative code is defining the contract with
用命令式代码定义合同
the compiler and the runtime so that the order of execution
编译器和运行时，以便执行顺序
is important. If we want to do repetition
很重要如果我们想重复
in imperative code then it is explicit.
在命令式代码中则是显式的。
We use an external loop where we define
我们使用一个外部循环来定义
a for loop with a particular construct, we have a while loop, we have a
具有特定结构的for循环，我们有一个while循环，我们有一个
do loop.
做循环。
These all explicit and we
这些都是明确的，我们
state our code how they are handled with
说明我们的代码如何处理
functional programming the values associated with names
函数式编程与名称关联的值
used as parameter. Their value is set once
用作参数。它们的值设置一次
and cannot be changed; that's a significant difference to imperative.
并且无法更改；这与当务之急有很大的不同。
How the function actually processes
函数实际如何处理
its information that the parameters in the data
其信息即数据中的参数
the order of execution is not defined so
执行顺序没有定义，所以
this is where the ability to apply parallel
这是并行应用的能力
processing to these things becomes much simpler because
处理这些事情变得更加简单，因为
we don't have to worry about the non-deterministic behavior
我们不必担心非确定性行为
of code when you start using multiple threads and breaking up the job in two
开始使用多个线程并将工作分解为两个时的代码片段
different
不同
tasks having those tasks potentially
有潜在任务的任务
processed in a different order. The way that we do repetition
以不同的顺序处理。我们重复的方式
through functional programming is using
通过函数式编程正在使用
recursion. You need to think when you're dealing with
递归。您在处理时需要思考
functional programming about
关于函数式编程
how you do things recursively rather than with an explicit loop.
您如何递归执行操作而不是使用显式循环。
And that is the end of section 1
至此第一节结束
of lesson 2.
第二课